# ALWIN WOO

alwinwoo@yahoo.com · +65 9877 3382 https://www.linkedin.com/in/alwinwoo · https://alwinwoo.github.io

#### CAREER SUMMARY

Alwin Woo is an accomplished professional with a diverse background in cybersecurity, data analytics, corporate strategy, finance and organisational development. With over 20 years of experience in several industries, he has a proven track record in implementing organisational plans to drive business transformation, lead complex projects, and build high-performing teams to help companies succeed.

### SKILLSETS

- Strategic Planning
- Corporate KPIs / Dashboard Reporting
- Policy Writing
- Project Management
- Change Management
   Data Analytics
- Risk ManagementMentoring
- Budgeting
- Cybersecurity

- Finance Reporting and Organisational Design and Development

### WORKING EXPERIENCE

## CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER ELYON INFINITE PTE LTD **OCT 2023** TO **PRESENT**

I lead the development and promotion of our email-based AI agent MINMEI. This includes designing and maintaining technical architecture, AI code and prompts, conducting business development activities, and staying updated on emerging AI technologies and industry events, particularly Al/Cybersecurity. Our Al agent was awarded NYP's Jumpstart Grant in 2023 and we are currently in the product development and market validation testing phase.

## SENIOR CONSULTANT EVVO LABS PTE LTD

#### NOV 2023 to JAN 2024

I aligned and prioritised company efforts to achieve the company's regional expansion plans, facilitated collaboration opportunities with international partners and built relationships with stakeholders. I refined internal processes and provided leadership to ensure key projects and initiatives were effectively planned, executed and monitored. I was part of Evvo's cybersecurity consultancy team providing CISO, DPO-aaS, cybersecurity consulting and risk assessment services for Cyber TrustMark, MAS TRM compliance and ISO27001 certification to our customers.

# Assistant Director (Finance) moh holdings pte Ltd

#### FEB 2017 to SEP 2022

I oversaw the company's annual workplanning cycle from collating submissions from business units to submission for budget approval by Board members. My team in MOHH organized workplan seminars and townhalls to disseminate work plans to all staff, help to orientate staff through engagement programmes and inculcated core values to promote desired organizational culture.

In 2021, I oversaw a business process review of our subsidiary's 1FSS call centre, review its business continuity plan and conducted the annual BCP exercise. We also conducted organizational climate surveys to understand staff sentiment, one of which was a nation-wide survey to understand the working experience of junior doctors done in 2019.

# Assistant Director (Office of Strategic Planning) singapore management university JUN 2015 to NOV 2016

I oversaw the annual workplanning cycle and tracking of corporate KPIs. I also prepared policy research papers such as reviewing projected annual SMU cohort intakes for the President and assisted in the SMU's Quality Assurance Framework for Universities (QAFU) assessment exercise.

# Assistant Director (strategy and business transformation) Health sciences authority MAR 2008 to JUN 2015

I oversaw the annual workplanning cycle and tracking of corporate KPIs. My team led the development of HSA's 5-year strategic plan, conducted retreats and management discussions, tracked and reported organizational KPIs, budget utilization, project initiatives and outcomes.

I supervised the Mapping of Manpower Capability and Identification of Skills Gaps exercise, led the HSA Horizon Scanning team as part of a corporate BPR exercise and headed the internal communications effort as part of the H1N1 Crisis Core team. I was the HSA Board, EXCO and Corporate Services Secretariat and helped formulate and implement R&D ethics approval and funding.

# MANAGER (THE ENTERPRISE CHALLENGE) PRIME MINISTER'S OFFICE

### APR 2006 to FEB 2008

I promoted the TEC innovation fund through roadshows, events and awards, identified and nurtured innovative ideas for funding, administer approved budgets and expenses, and recommended rectification actions when required.

# PRUDENTIAL ADVISER PRUDENTIAL ASSURANCE COMPANY SINGAPORE

#### **SEP 2004** TO MAR 2006

I sought out prospects, understand their financial needs and conducted analysis to recommend suitable products to achieve their desired life outcomes.

# ACCOUNT MANAGER (ARMY AND AIRFORCE) DSO NATIONAL LABORATORIES JAN 2000 to AUG 2004

I supported workplanning efforts to engage Army and Airforce key appointment holders, help connect customers to specialists within the company and supported major events promoting defence and R&D such as Asian Aerospace, Army, Airforce and Navy Open Houses.

## **E**DUCATION

- 2023 Specialist diploma in business and big data analytics, nanyang polytechnic certified in cybersecurity cc, (ISC)<sup>2</sup>
- 2020 FUNDAMENTALS OF THE PDPA ACT, NTUC LEARNING HUB
- 2012 PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL PMP, PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE
- 2002 MASTER OF ENGINEERING SCIENCE (TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT), UNIVERSITY OF NEW SOUTH WALES
- 1999 BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (MECHANICAL) HONS,
  NANYANG TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY
- 1995 GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN MARKETING, CHARTERED INSTITUTE OF MARKETING, UK

## **A**CTIVITIES

Mentoring, Programming, Writing, Reading, Swimming

### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Python, PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Tableau, SAS Viya, KNIME, Linux, C++